<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The French King's reasons for owning the pretended Prince of Wales, King of England, Scotland and Ireland. Communicated in a letter from Paris, to a gentleman in London.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 3 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B16483</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99893257</idno>
  <idno type="VID">188806</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240933877</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Thomason E.1963[18]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide E.1963[18]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC T113677</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99893257</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99893257e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B16483)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 188806)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; C13:1[17])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The French King's reasons for owning the pretended Prince of Wales, King of England, Scotland and Ireland. Communicated in a letter from Paris, to a gentleman in London.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>4 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>printed for J.N. near Ludgate,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1701]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Imprint from colophon.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="personal_name">James, --  Prince of Wales, 1688-1766 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-02 </date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-08 </date>
            <label>Colm MacCrossan </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-08 </date>
            <label>Colm MacCrossan</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="account">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:188806:1"/>
            <head>THE <hi>French King</hi>'s REASONS For Owning the Pretended <hi>Prince of Wales,</hi> King of <hi>England, Scotland</hi> and <hi>Ireland. Communicated in a Letter from</hi> Paris, <hi>to a Gentle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man in</hi> London.</head>
            <opener>
               <dateline>
                  <hi>Paris</hi>
                  <date>the 18th of <hi>September,</hi> 1701.</date>
               </dateline>
               <salute>SIR,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>IT is no wonder you are Inquisitive in <hi>England,</hi> how His Maiesty wou'd Act towards the Prince of <hi>Wales,</hi> when it pleas'd God to take the <hi>King</hi> his Father to his Mercy.</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="tcp:188806:2"/>
            <p>I suppose 'tis no News to you, that the Prince Assum'd the Stile and Dignity of King of <hi>England;</hi> as soon as his Father the Late King Dy'd, being a Title Devolv'd to him as his Son and Heir. Nor has there been any Difficulty made in <hi>France,</hi> to Own him in that Quality, his most Christian Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jesty, having declar'd his Intentions of doing so sometimes before his Father's Death, for Treating him as Prince of <hi>Wales</hi> in his Father's Life time; 'twas a Natural Consequence, that after his Decease, he wou'd call him King of <hi>England.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Neither do we conceive that any Umbrage can be taken at this, since we don't Apprehend that there lies on Us any Engagement or Obligation to the contrary; That there can none arise from the Treaty of <hi>Reswick</hi> is Obvious enough, since the 4th Article of that Treaty, Imports only his most Christian Majesty shall not Trouble the King of <hi>England</hi> in the Possession of his Dominions; and that he should not either with Troops, Ships, nor any other Supplies, Assist such as would give him a Disturbance.</p>
            <p>His Majesty will Punctually Observe this Article, and the Character of King of <hi>England,</hi> which the Prince of <hi>Wales</hi> thought himself Indispensably Oblig'd to take after his Father's Death, do's not Entile him to any Succors from <hi>France,</hi> besides such as his Father receiv'd since the Treaty of <hi>Reswick,</hi> and are design'd only for his Subsistance, and to Condole him under his Misfortunes.</p>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:188806:2"/>
            <p>His Majesty's Generosity wou'd not permit him to Abandon either the Prince, or his Family; and his Majesty (being no Arbiter between the King of Great <hi>Britain,</hi> and the Prince of <hi>Wales)</hi> could not do so Decisive a thing against the latter, as to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cline Owning him, by a Title which is Deriv'd to him from his Birth.</p>
            <p>It's no New thing to Continue to the Children, the Titles of Kingdoms which their Fathers have Lost; it has been done without Scruple by Princes, who at the same time were in Peace with the present Possessors. History Furnishs one with fre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quent Examples among the King of <hi>Naples</hi> and <hi>Narvar,</hi> and not to enlarge on this head: We know that the Kings of <hi>Poland,</hi> of the House of <hi>Vasa,</hi> retain'd the Stile of Kings of <hi>Sweden,</hi> eve till the Peace of <hi>Oliva,</hi> tho' that Treaty was made long as<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>their Expulsion, and they had Engag'd in streight Alliances, both with King <hi>Gustavus,</hi> and Queen <hi>Christina,</hi> in the Interim.</p>
            <p>His Majesty has Declar'd, that his Intention is only to Treat the Prince of <hi>Wales,</hi> with the same Regard he has Express'd towards the Late King his Father, since the Peace of <hi>Reswick;</hi> and that he has no Thoughts of Disturbing the Repose of <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land,</hi> on any Pretext whatsoever.</p>
            <pb n="4" facs="tcp:188806:3"/>
            <p>And certainly the measures His Majesty has Ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>serv'd at this Conjuncture, are both Just, and Exact<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly Pursuant to his Treaties, as well as to what his Honour requires from him, tho' at the same time it may be Urg'd, that his Neighbours have not always Acted with a suitable Tenderness, in making such Movements, as might be agreeable to His Majesty.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>
                  <hi>I am,</hi> &amp;c</signed>.</closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for <hi>J. N.</hi> near <hi>Ludgate,</hi> 1701.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:188806:3"/>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>